<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife (MDIFW)</origin>
				<pubdate>2009-10-28</pubdate>
				<title Sync="TRUE">gisdata.GISADMIN.gisdata_GISADMIN_Habitat_Waterfowl</title>
				<geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
				<serinfo>
					<sername>Maine GIS</sername>
					<issue>SDE server; Internet Data Catalog</issue>
				</serinfo>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
					<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink Sync="TRUE">Service=sde:sqlserver:gis; Database=gisdata; User=gisadmin; Version=sde.DEFAULT</onlink>
				<ftname Sync="TRUE">gisdata.GISADMIN.gisdata_GISADMIN_Habitat_Waterfowl</ftname></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>This layer represents Inland Waterfowl / Wading bird Habitat (IWWH), a Significant Wildlife Habitat defined under Maine's Natural Resources Protection Act (NRPA; http://www.maine.gov/dep/blwq/docstand/nrpapage.htm).  IWWHs with a high or moderate rating meet the Significant Wildlife Habitat definition and are protected under NRPA.  Low-rated IWWHs are NOT included in this layer because they do not meet the definition and are not protected under NRPA.  Boundaries and attributes of polygons in organized townships were updated in 2008 by MDIFW staff using recent (2001-2007), high-resolution (&lt;=1 m), color orthoimagery.  For most polygons, multiple images from different years and seasons were used.  Polygons in unorganized townships were mapped by MDIFW regional staff in the 1990s from lower-resolution orthoimagery, various wetland data sets, and field visits or via an automated process developed by Heather Rustigian and William Krohn (USGS Biological Resources Division) using statewide digital NWI (National Wetlands Inventory) data, aerial imagery, and hydrology data.  Each IWWH boundary includes a 250-foot upland zone around the wetland perimeter.  Upland zones were edited to exclude areas of intensive development, slivers crossing major roads into non-wetland habitat, and shorelines &gt;250 ft from a vegetated, non-forested wetland on a Great Pond.  Updated 2009-10-28.</abstract>
			<purpose>Polygons with a high or moderate rating indicate Inland Waterfowl / Wading bird Habitats (IWWHs) protected as Significant Wildlife Habitats under NRPA.  NRPA-protected IWWHs with a non-forested wetland size (indicated in the SZ_ACREAGE field) of at least 10 acres are also protected under Municipal Shoreland Zoning (MSZ).  Because NRPA allows ratings and boundaries of IWWHs to be changed based on site visits by MDIFW Regional Staff, whereas MSZ polygons are fixed as of Nov 20, 2008, a separate layer called "Shorezone_Iwwh" in the MEGIS Data Catalog and "MEIFW.Iwwh_SZ_New" in the SDE catalog was created on Nov 20, 2008 to specifically depict MSZ-protected IWWHs. </purpose>
			<supplinf>Five criteria are used to rate IWWHs as high, moderate, or low value: (1) wetland type composition, (2) number of different wetland types, (3) size, (4) interspersion, and (5) percent of open water.  For further information on this rating system please refer to the following document: "GIS-Based Evaluation of Waterfowl and Wading Bird Habitats in Maine" by Heather L. Rustigian and William B. Krohn, University of Maine, Orono, Final Contract Report to the Maine Dept. Inland Fisheries and Wildlife, Augusta, Maine, June 2002.  Not all ratings have been field verified.</supplinf>
			<langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>2009-10-28</caldate>
					<time>unknown</time>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Irregular</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc Sync="TRUE">-71.159484</westbc>
				<eastbc Sync="TRUE">-66.895774</eastbc>
				<northbc Sync="TRUE">47.457496</northbc>
				<southbc Sync="TRUE">43.060021</southbc>
			</bounding>
			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">337171.071700</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">658659.394000</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">4769420.457000</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">5256005.999900</topbc></lboundng></spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO Keyword Thesaurus</themekt>
				<themekey>environment</themekey>
				<themekey>biota</themekey>
				<themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
				<themekey>shoreland zoning</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>Maine GIS Thesaurus-Theme</themekt>
				<themekey>National Wetlands Inventory</themekey>
				<themekey>natural resource protection act</themekey>
				<themekey>significant wildlife habitat</themekey>
				<themekey>inland wading bird habitat</themekey>
				<themekey>inland waterfowl habitat</themekey>
				<themekey>shoreland zoning</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>Maine GIS Thesaurus-Place</placekt>
				<placekey>Maine</placekey>
				<placekey>United States</placekey>
			</place>
			<stratum>
				<stratkt>GCMD Parameter Keyword</stratkt>
				<stratkey>biosphere</stratkey>
				<stratkey>hydrosphere</stratkey>
			</stratum>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>This data is public information provided by Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife through the Maine Office of GIS (MEGIS).  The MEGIS Data Catalog is the only source of this data that MDIFW ensures is current; copies of this data obtained from other sources (including the Maine Dept. of Environmental Protection's Google Earth webpage http://www.maine.gov/dep/gis/datamaps/, may be out of date.</accconst>
		<useconst>These data are provided by the Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife for determining inland waterfowl / wading bird habitats protected under the Natural Resources Protection Act (NRPA) and shoreland zoning.  Only polygons with a high or moderate rating qualify under NRPA.  Only polygons that qualify under NRPA and have a wetland size of at least 10 acres qualify under shoreland zoning.  Users assume all responsiblity for using this data as intended and all liability for using this data other than as intended.  This data is not intended to be used at scales below 1:6,000.  To ensure that this data is the most current version available, download this data directly from the Maine Office of GIS or from an official, state of Maine webservice that accesses this data directly from the MEGIS data catalog.  In the use of Maine GIS data, please check sources, scale, accuracy, currentness and other available information. Please confirm that you are using the correct copy of both data and metadata from the Maine GIS Data Catalog. The Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS) provides notice of updates and corrections directly to the Maine GIS Technical Group and Maine GIS Users, through the MEGISTECH and MEGISUSER list servers. To subscribe please contact MeGIS through the Maine Office of Information Technology (OIT) Customer Support Center (CSC) at (207) 624-7700. To request data correction in, or provide updates to Maine GIS data, please use the contact information contained in the metadata. Updates, corrections, and feedback, incorporated in the Maine GIS database are made in accordance with "Data Standards for Maine Geographic Information Systems", 2002, and coordinated by MEGIS in consultation with the Maine GIS Executive Council.</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>(MDIFW) Maine Dept of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife</cntorg>
					<cntper>Donald Katnik</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Habitat Group Leader</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>650 State Street</address>
					<city>Bangor</city>
					<state>Maine</state>
					<postal>04401</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>207 941-4455</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>207 941-4450</cntfax>
				<cntemail>donald.katnik@maine.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>Monday - Friday 8:00am-4:00pm EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<datacred>Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife (MDIFW) Wildlife Resource Assessment Section, Habitat Group; MDIFW Wildlife Management Section, Regional staff; Heather L. Rustigian and William B. Krohn, University of Maine, Maine Cooperative Fish and Wildlife Research Unit (for polygons mapped in unorganized townships) .</datacred>
		<native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.4000</native>
		<natvform Sync="TRUE">SDE Feature Class</natvform></idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<complete>The dataset is complete as of 2009-10-28</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>Approximate horizontal accuracy is 12 meters plus or minus 40 feet or better, assuming source data meets National Map Accuracy Standards.</horizpar>
				<qhorizpa>
					<horizpav>12</horizpav>
					<horizpae>Data was derived from digital data that meets or exceeds National Map Accuracy Standards for 1:24,000 scale.</horizpae>
				</qhorizpa>
			</horizpa>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFW) National Wetlands Inventory (NWI) Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS) (ed.)</origin>
						<pubdate>1998</pubdate>
						<pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
						<title>nwi</title>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Maine GIS</sername>
							<issue>SDE server; Internet Data Catalog</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>MEGIS Library and Data Catalog</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>1:24000 For more information on the Cowardin System see L.M.Cowardin, et al, 1979 "Classification of Wetland and Deepwater Habitats of the United States". U.S. Department of the Interior, Fish and Wildlife Service FWS/OBS-79/31.  http://www.nwi.fws.gov/Pubs_Reports/Class_Manual/class_titlepg.htm</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>197102</begdate>
							<begtime>unknown</begtime>
							<enddate>199212</enddate>
							<endtime>unknown</endtime>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>source dates</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>nwi</srccitea>
				<srccontr>National Wetlands Inventory used to derive original Iwwh boundaries and automated ratings.  Used in current updated as a guide to wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Digital Globe, Maine Department of Environmental Protection (MEDEP)</origin>
						<pubdate>20051107</pubdate>
						<title>ortho_bp</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Baxter State Park Quick Bird Imagery</sername>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Longmont CO</pubplace>
							<publish>Digital Globe</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>3600</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>20031003</begdate>
							<begtime>unknown</begtime>
							<enddate>20051029</enddate>
							<endtime>unknown</endtime>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>flight dates</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>ortho_bp</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS) (comp., ed.)</origin>
						<pubdate>2004</pubdate>
						<pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
						<title>hyd24</title>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Maine GIS</sername>
							<issue>SDE server; Internet Data Catalog</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>
1:24000 For distribution through the Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog this dataset is distributed by HUC8 watershed map extent. A list of all twenty-one (21) HUC8 names and numbers is available in a table "HUCLUT", at the Data Catalog "Tables" link. Corresponding 12 digit HUC names and numbers are also included in the table. Three methods of selection are available from the Internet Data Catalog to suit your needs:

1) To obtain a downloadable list of all the HUC8 watersheds use Select by County on HYD24, and select all counties. The result will be by county and include all HUC8 watershed names and numbers with some, but minimum, overlap to choose from for download.

2) If you want to limit your download to a specific hydrography feature use Select by Watershed, which will provide a list of HUC12 names of local features to select from. The result will provide only the corresponding 8 digit HUCs to download.

3) For advanced search and query statewide, download the data layer WBDME6_A. The data layer contains boundaries, name and number attribution for 6, 8, 10, 12 digit HUCs and can be used as an index for each of these levels of watersheds.
</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>24000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>2004</caldate>
							<time>unknown</time>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>source dates</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>hyd24</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Hydrography data used to determine water flow through wetland systems</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Maine Library of Geographic Information (MLGI), U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)(comp.)</origin>
						<pubdate>20041201</pubdate>
						<pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
						<title>ortho_1f</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Maine GIS</sername>
							<issue>SDE server; Internet Data Catalog</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>1:2400</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>2400</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>20030301</begdate>
							<begtime>unknown</begtime>
							<enddate>20030519</enddate>
							<endtime>unknown</endtime>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>ortho_1f</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Maine Library of Geographic Information (MLGI), U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)(comp.)</origin>
						<pubdate>20041201</pubdate>
						<pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
						<title>ortho_2f</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Maine GIS</sername>
							<issue>SDE server; Internet Data Catalog</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>1:4800</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>4800</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>20030301</begdate>
							<begtime>unknown</begtime>
							<enddate>20030519</enddate>
							<endtime>unknown</endtime>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>ortho_2f</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Bradstreet Consultants, Inc. (www.bradstreet.com), Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (comp.)</origin>
						<pubdate>20040216</pubdate>
						<title>ortho_ff</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Maine GIS</sername>
							<issue>SDE server; Internet Data Catalog</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>
1:1200 ORTHO_FF consists of high resolution, 24-bit color orthophotography. Flown in May 2003 the ortho-rectified digital imagery covers all of Fort Fairfield, Maine. These digital images have a pixel resolution (or ground sample distance GSD) of 1/2 foot, are precision geo-referenced and ortho-rectified, and accurate for 1"=100' mapping applications.  The digital orthoimagery has been made available by the Bradstreet Consultants, Inc. and the  Town of Fort Fairfield.

Original file sizes were: 100 images at 1800 meters by 1200 meters, butt matched with no overlap and an image file size of 281 MB; and 24 images at 900 meters by 600 meters, with a file size of 70 MB and also butt matched with no overlap.  For distribution in the Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog the 24, 900 meter x 600 meter files, were appended into 6, 1800 meter by 1200 meter files. The lower left or southwestern-most photo number was used to identify each of the appended tiles. A file index, INDEX_FF reflects this change recording 106 reference numbers.
</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>1200</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>20030520</caldate>
							<time>unknown</time>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>flight date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>ortho_ff</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>GlobeXplorer, Maine Library of Geographic Information (MLGI), Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)(comp.)</origin>
						<pubdate>200307</pubdate>
						<title>ortho_hf</title>
						<edition>200104</edition>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>CITIPIX Ortho-rectified Digital Images (ODI)</sername>
							<issue>2001</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>1:1200 (MEGIS) ORTHO_HF consists of 906 tiles of high resolution, 24-bit color aerial photography. These GLOBEXPLORER CITIPIX digital images have a pixel resolution (or ground sample distance) of 1/2 foot, are precision geo-referenced and ortho-rectified, and accurate for 1"=100' mapping applications. Flown in April 2001, from Portland to Auburn ME the ortho-rectified digital imagery covers all of Cumberland County and part of Androscoggin County, Maine.</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>1200</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>200104</caldate>
							<time>unknown</time>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>flight date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>ortho_hf</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Delorme, Inc., Maine State Planning Office (MESPO), Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)(comp.)</origin>
						<pubdate>200401</pubdate>
						<title>ortho_mcp</title>
						<edition>200306</edition>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>Delorme Ortho-rectified Digital Images (ODI)</sername>
							<issue>2003</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Augusta ME</pubplace>
							<publish>Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>2400 (MEGIS) ORTHO_MCP consists of 12-bit color aerial photography taken at low tide.  These Delorme digital images have a pixel resolution (or ground sample distance) of 1 foot, are precision geo-referenced and ortho-rectified, and accurate for 1"=200' mapping applications. Flown on June 6, 2003.</othercit>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>2400</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>200306</caldate>
							<time>Unknown</time>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>ortho_mcp</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) EROS Data Center (EDC)</origin>
						<pubdate>19970514</pubdate>
						<title>doqq</title>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>USGS Aerial Photography</sername>
							<issue>Digital Orthophoto Quadrangles</issue>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Menlo Park, CA USA</pubplace>
							<publish>
U.S. Geological Survey
U.S. Geological Survey
</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<othercit>
1:12000 A digital orthophoto is a computer-generated image of an aerial photograph in which the image displacement caused by terrain relief and camera tilt has been removed.

A digital orthophoto can be incorporated into any geographic information system (GIS) that can manipulate raster images. It can function as a cartographic base for displaying, generating, and modifying associated digital planimetric data. Other applications include vegetation and timber management, routing and habitat analysis, environmental impact assessments, emergency evacuation planning, flood analysis, soil erosion assessment, facility management, and groundwater and watershed analysis. The accuracy and extraordinary detail provided by the digital orthophoto allow users to evaluate their data for accuracy and completeness, make real-time modifications to their data, and even generate new files.

DOQQ is a mosaic of digital orthophoto quarter quadrangles stored in a Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS) Oracle/ArcSDE environment. The digital orthophoto quarter quadrangles that form  the mosaic are available for download from the Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog in compressed MrSID format in 7.5 minute quadrangle map extent. Compression with LizardTech's MrSID software creates two files a .sid image and an .sdw file georeferencing file, approximate size of the download is 12MB, one sixteenth of the uncompressed DOQQ image.
</othercit>
						<onlink>http://megisims.state.me.us/website/orthomap/viewer.htm</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>12000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>19960507</begdate>
							<begtime>Unknown</begtime>
							<enddate>19990610</enddate>
							<endtime>Unknown</endtime>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>doqq</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, black&amp;white othorimagery used only where no other imagery was available to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>USDA National Agriculture Imagery Program</origin>
						<pubdate>2007-08</pubdate>
						<title>NAIP 2007</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>National Agriculture Imagery Program</sername>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<publish>USDA</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>12000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>2007-08</caldate>
							<time>unknown</time>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>Naip2007</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>USDA National Agriculture Imagery Program</origin>
						<pubdate>2006-08</pubdate>
						<title>NAIP 2006</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<serinfo>
							<sername>National Agriculture Imagery Program</sername>
						</serinfo>
						<pubinfo>
							<publish>USDA</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://megis.maine.gov/catalog/</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>12000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>200608</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>Naip2006</srccitea>
				<srccontr>High-resolution, color othorimagery used to delineate wetland boundaries and types.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>
Five criteria are used to assess IWWHs: dominant wetland type, wetland type diversity, habitat size, wetland type interspersion, and amount of open water.  A high to moderate value inland habitat is an inland wetland complex, and a 250 ft upland area, that through a combination of the five criteria listed above, meets MDIFW guidelines or is an inland wetland complex or has documented outstanding use by waterfowl or wading birds.  For further information on this rating system please refer to the following document: "GIS-Based Evaluation of Waterfowl and Wading Bird Habitats in Maine" by Heather L. Rustigian and William B. Krohn, University of Maine, Orono, Final Contract Report to the Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife, Augusta, Maine, June 2002.  Not all ratings have been field verified.

Iwwh boundaries and ratings were re-evaluated in 2007-08 using newer, higher-resolution, color orthoimagery.  In many places, multiple images from different years and seasons were available.  

Upland zones 250 feet in diameter around each Iwwh complex were edited to exclude areas of intense development, areas across roads where it was determined that excluding the area would not affect the ecological integrity of the wetland complex, and shoreline around Great Ponds &gt;250 feet from a non-forested, vegetated wetland.
</procdesc>
				<procdate>20081231</procdate>
				<proccont>
					<cntinfo>
						<cntorgp>
							<cntorg>(Katnik)Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife</cntorg>
							<cntper>Donald Katnik</cntper>
						</cntorgp>
						<cntpos>Habitat Group Leader</cntpos>
						<cntaddr>
							<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
							<address>650 State Street</address>
							<city>Bangor</city>
							<state>ME</state>
							<postal>04401</postal>
							<country>USA</country>
						</cntaddr>
						<cntvoice>207 941 445</cntvoice>
						<cntfax>207 941 4450</cntfax>
						<cntemail>donald.katnik@maine.gov</cntemail>
						<hours>Monday - Friday 8:00AM-4:00PM EST</hours>
					</cntinfo>
				</proccont>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\DONALD~1.IFW\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml1A0.tmp</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\DONALD~1.IFW\LOCALS~1\Temp\xmlBE.tmp</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\DONALD~1.IFW\LOCALS~1\Temp\xmlD.tmp</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\DONALD~1.IFW\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml172.tmp</srcused>
				<procdate>20081222</procdate>
				<proctime>13065600</proctime>
			</procstep>
			<procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">C:\DOCUME~1\DONALD~1.KAT\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml5.tmp</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20081224</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">07472500</proctime></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">Server=gisdatabase.dafs.state.me.us; Service=5154/tcp; User=meifw; Version=SDE.DEFAULT</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20090517</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">16132900</proctime></procstep></lineage>
		<cloud>0</cloud>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf><esriterm Name="WadingbirdWaterfowl"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">0</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<planci>
					<plance Sync="TRUE">coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres Sync="TRUE">0.000328</absres>
						<ordres Sync="TRUE">0.000328</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu Sync="TRUE">survey feet</plandu>
				</planci>
			</planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips Sync="TRUE">Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
			<cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Maine_East_FIPS_1801_Feet</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>
		<vertdef>
			<altsys>
				<altres Sync="TRUE">1.000000</altres>
				<altenc Sync="TRUE">Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc>
			</altsys>
		</vertdef>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="WadingbirdWaterfowl">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl Sync="TRUE">WadingbirdWaterfowl</enttypl>
				<enttypd>polygon feature class</enttypd>
				<enttypds>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</enttypds>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">0</enttypc></enttyp>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Notes</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Notes entered by mapper to describe any irregularities in the Iwwh boundary or rating</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>MDIFW</attrdefs>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">NOTES</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">254</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">TOTAL_ACRE</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">TOTAL_ACRE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><attrdef>Iwwh wetland acreage (does not include the 250-foot upland zone)</attrdef><attrdefs>MDIFW</attrdefs><atprecis Sync="TRUE">18</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">8</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SZ_ACREAGE</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SZ_ACREAGE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><attrdef>Iwwh wetland acreage for Shoreland Zoning (does not include forested wetlands or the 250-foot upland zone; Iwwhs &gt;= 10 acres qualify under shoreland zoning)</attrdef><attrdefs>MDIFW</attrdefs><atprecis Sync="TRUE">18</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">8</attscale></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>Iwwh_ID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Wetland complex identification number</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>MDIFW</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Values beginning with "IFW"</edomv>
						<edomvd>Mapped by MDIFW Regional Staff in the 1990s primarily using black &amp; white orthoimagery, assorted wetland data, and field visits.</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Values beginning with "Iwwh" and a number below 200000</edomv>
						<edomvd>Updated in 2008 using 2001-07 color orthoimagery with at least 1 m resolution.  These wetlands were orginally mapped by MDIFW Regional Staff.</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Values beginning with "Iwwh" and a number above 200000</edomv>
						<edomvd>Updated in 2008 using 2001-07 color orthoimagery with at least 1 m resolution.  These wetlands were orginally mapped by the University of Maine automated process using National Wetlands Inventory data.</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Values beginning with "UMO"</edomv>
						<edomvd>Mapped by an automated process developed by the University of Maine using the National Wetlands Inventory data.</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">IWWH_ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">15</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Rating</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>NRPA Rating based on Total Score (High and Moderate value qualify under NRPA)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>MDIFW</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>H (High)</edomv>
						<edomvd>High-value wetland for inland waterfowl and wading birds as defined under Maine's Natural Resources Protection Act</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>M (Moderate)</edomv>
						<edomvd>Moderate-value wetland for inland waterfowl and wading birds as defined under Maine's Natural Resources Protection Act</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>L (Low)</edomv>
						<edomvd>Low-value wetland for inland waterfowl and wading birds as defined under Maine's Natural Resources Protection Act.  Low-value Iwwhs are NOT considered Significant Wildlife Habitats under NRPA</edomvd>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">RATING</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shoreland</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shoreland</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>Site_Rated</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>"Y" means Rating is based on a site visit, not on the numeric score</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>MDIFW</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Y</edomv>
						<edomvd>Text rating (High, Moderate, or Low) is based on a site visit</edomvd>
						<edomvds>MDIFW</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>N</edomv>
						<edomvd>Text score (High, Moderate, or Low) is based on the Score</edomvd>
						<edomvds>MDIFW</edomvds>
					</edom>
					<udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">SITE_RATED</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape_area</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_area</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape_len</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_len</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed>
		<overview>
			<eadetcit>The ArcInfo coverage, ArcView shapefile, ArcGIS geodatabase formats, commonly used for Maine GIS data, carry default identifiers and attributes that are software generated and/or important for internal recordkeeping. These are listed here to avoid repetition for every layer, and may not be repeated in the attribute descriptions and definitions of each layer. Common software generated identifiers and attributes in Maine GIS data include: &lt;title&gt;#, &lt;title&gt;-ID, &lt;title&gt;_, &lt;title&gt;_ID, FID (feature identifier), Shape (feature geometry), OBJECTID. Other default attributes, that may be present, refer to the topological relationships between features, for example RIGHTPOLY or R_POLY, LEFTPOLY or L_POLY, FROMNODE or F_NODE, TONODE or T_NODE. In addition, most GIS formats will carry fields for PERIMETER, AREA and/or LENGTH according to feature geometry. These fields are typically available by default, with the units based on coordinate system or projection units of GIS data. (Units are meters for Maine GIS data.) Most GIS software packages also provide a means to calculate these values. It is important to test any columns containing PERIMETER, AREA or LENGTH values before using them for analysis purposes. These important values can be carried from format to format and become out-dated. Verify that the values are correct. Also, in your GIS software, please view the properties of data layers for the map units used to calculate these fields, and for the units set for display purposes.</eadetcit>
		</overview>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>(MEGIS) Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>State House Station 145</address>
					<city>Augusta</city>
					<state>ME</state>
					<postal>04333-0145</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(207) 624-7700</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>(207) 287-4563</cntfax>
				<hours>Monday through Friday 0800 - 1700 EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
		<distliab>Users must assume responsibility to determine the usability of this data for their purposes. Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer system at the Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems, no warranty expressed or implied is made by MEGIS regarding the utility of the data on any other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. Neither the Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems, nor any of its contributors, is liable for misuse of the data, for damage, for transmission of viruses, or for computer contamination through the distribution of these data sets.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>ESRI Shapefile</formname>
					<formvern>ARC Version 9.x</formvern>
					<formspec>ArcView Shapefile Format</formspec>
					<formcont>MEGIS has made all vector layers, in the Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog, available in ESRI's ArcView shapefile format. A shapefile is a simple non-topological format that stores the geometry and attribute information for a set of geographic features as a set of vector (point, line, polygon) coordinates. Shapefiles draw quickly and directly in ArcView, ArcGIS, ArcExplorer. Shapefiles are a compatible data type for many other types of GIS software. Three files are fundamental to each shapefile: .shp stores the feature geometry (shape and location information); .shx stores the index of the feature geometry; .dbf a dBASE (TM) file stores the attribute information for the features. Other index files may be created to help speed analysis and query: these file formats are .sbn  .sbx  .ain .aix .fbn and .fbx. In addition you may find projection .prj, and metadata .xml, files associated with shapefiles.</formcont>
					<filedec>Data available from this website is in .zip compressed format. WinZip is a Windows based, PKZip-compatible compression utility. You will need a program like this to extract the data. A link to a trial copy WinZip software is available at http://megis.maine.gov/links/.</filedec>
					<transize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transize><dssize Sync="TRUE">0.000</dssize></digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<accinstr>These data are available to Internet browsers for download from the Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog. Data available from this website is in .zip compressed format. WinZip is a Windows based, PKZip-compatible compression utility. You will need a program like this to extract the data. A link to a trial copy WinZip software is available at http://megis.maine.gov/links/. If you are not already a GIS user, free software for viewing these files is available from Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI). See http://megis.maine.gov/links/ for a link to ArcExplorer 9.x .</accinstr>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<accinstr>Where file size and Internet access permit, data requests can be made available via File Transfer Protocol (FTP).</accinstr>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>Data may be downloaded from Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog at no charge.</fees>
			<turnarnd>Data is available for immediate download from the Maine GIS Internet Data Catalog.</turnarnd>
		</stdorder>
		<custom>MEGIS provides technical support for Maine GIS data, estimates on custom mapping, and consultation on data and application development, as time permits. Please call (207) 624-7700 with questions about Maine GIS data, or to inquire about assistance with your GIS environment.</custom>
		<availabl>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>2009-10-28</caldate>
					<time>unknown</time>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
		</availabl>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>2009-10-28</metd>
		<metrd>2009-10-28</metrd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>(Katnik)Maine Department of Inland Fisheries and Wildlife</cntorg>
					<cntper>Donald Katnik</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Habitat Group Leader</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>650 State Street</address>
					<city>Bangor</city>
					<state>ME</state>
					<postal>04401</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>207 941 4455</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>207 941 4450</cntfax>
				<cntemail>donald.katnik@maine.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>Monday - Friday 8:00AM-4:00PM EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
		<metuc>Please confirm that you are using the correct copy of both data and metadata from the Maine GIS Data Catalog. The Maine Office of Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS) provides notice of updates and corrections directly to the Maine GIS Technical Group and Maine GIS Users through the MEGISTECH and MEGISUSER list servers. To subscribe please contact MeGIS through the Maine Office of Information Technology (OIT) Customer Support Center (CSC) at (207) 624-7700. To request correction in, or updates to Maine GIS data, please use the contact information contained in the metadata. Updates, corrections, and feedback incorporated in the Maine GIS database are made in accordance with "Data Standards for Maine Geographic Information Systems", 2002, and coordinated by MEGIS in consultation with the Maine GIS Executive Council.</metuc>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta></metainfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20090517</CreaDate><CreaTime>16132900</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20130510</SyncDate><SyncTime>14231100</SyncTime><ModDate>20130510</ModDate><ModTime>14231100</ModTime><MetaID>{51DA6941-382E-4F63-AC93-BED49AB61CFD}</MetaID><DataProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Conversion Tools.tbx\FeatureClassToFeatureClass" Date="20091104" Time="083518">FeatureClassToFeatureClass "Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh" C:\temp iwwh.shp # "IWWH_ID 'IWWH_ID' true true false 15 Text 0 0 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,IWWH_ID,-1,-1;TOTAL_ACRE 'TOTAL_ACRE' true true false 8 Double 8 38 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,TOTAL_ACRE,-1,-1;RATING 'RATING' true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,RATING,-1,-1;NOTES 'NOTES' true true false 255 Text 0 0 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,NOTES,-1,-1;SZ_ACREAGE 'SZ_ACREAGE' true true false 8 Double 8 38 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,SZ_ACREAGE,-1,-1;SITE_RATED 'SITE_RATED' true true false 1 Text 0 0 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,SITE_RATED,-1,-1;SHAPE_AREA 'SHAPE_AREA' false false true 0 Double 0 0 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,SHAPE.AREA,-1,-1;SHAPE_LEN 'SHAPE_LEN' false false true 0 Double 0 0 ,First,#,Database Connections\moeprodr2.megis.sde\MEIFW.Iwwh,SHAPE.LEN,-1,-1" # C:\temp\iwwh.shp</Process><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Conversion Tools.tbx\FeatureClassToFeatureClass" Date="20100602" Time="092148">FeatureClassToFeatureClass "C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp" "Database Connections\gisadmin@gisdata@gis.sde" Waterfowl_Habitat # "IWWH_ID 'IWWH_ID' true true false 15 Text 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,IWWH_ID,-1,-1;TOTAL_ACRE 'TOTAL_ACRE' true true false 19 Double 8 18 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,TOTAL_ACRE,-1,-1;RATING 'RATING' true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,RATING,-1,-1;NOTES 'NOTES' true true false 254 Text 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,NOTES,-1,-1;SZ_ACREAGE 'SZ_ACREAGE' true true false 19 Double 8 18 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,SZ_ACREAGE,-1,-1;SITE_RATED 'SITE_RATED' true true false 1 Text 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,SITE_RATED,-1,-1;SHAPE_AREA 'SHAPE_AREA' true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,SHAPE_AREA,-1,-1;SHAPE_LEN 'SHAPE_LEN' true true false 19 Double 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,SHAPE_LEN,-1,-1;Shoreland 'Shoreland' true true false 1 Text 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\sgambrel\Desktop\New Folder\iwwh.shp,Shoreland,-1,-1" # "Database Connections\gisadmin@gisdata@gis.sde\gisdata.GISADMIN.Waterfowl_Habitat"</Process><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CopyFeatures" Date="20121029" Time="105641">CopyFeatures B:\Projects\Administrator\_Data\gisadmin@gisdata@gis.sde\gisdata.GISADMIN.Habitat_Waterfowl B:\Projects\Administrator\_Data\gisadmin@gisdata@gis.sde\gisdata.GISADMIN.HABITAT\gisdata.GISADMIN.gisdata_GISADMIN_Habitat_Waterfowl # 0 0 0</Process><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\desktop10.1\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CopyFeatures" Date="20130510" Time="142312">CopyFeatures B:\Projects\Administrator\_Data\SDE@gisdata@gis.sde\gisdata.GISADMIN.HABITAT\gisdata.GISADMIN.WadingbirdWaterfowl "B:\Projects\Administrator\MISC PROJECTS\SHP for Garrett Wilkin\Set 1\Habitat\WadingbirdWaterfowl.shp" # 0 0 0</Process></lineage><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">WadingbirdWaterfowl</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><itemSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</itemSize><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\GIS\GIS_Data\Projects\Administrator\MISC PROJECTS\SHP for Garrett Wilkin\Set 1\Habitat\WadingbirdWaterfowl.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Foot_US (0.304801)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Maine_East_FIPS_1801_Feet</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.1'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;NAD_1983_StatePlane_Maine_East_FIPS_1801_Feet&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Transverse_Mercator&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,984250.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-68.5],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Scale_Factor&amp;quot;,0.9999],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,43.66666666666666],UNIT[&amp;quot;Foot_US&amp;quot;,0.3048006096012192],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;,26847]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-17462500&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-48679000&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;137255069.87923574&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.0032808333333333331&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;102683&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;26847&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef></DataProperties></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.1.0.3035</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="eng"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">WadingbirdWaterfowl</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">337171.0717</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">658659.394</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">5256005.9999</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4769420.457</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-71.159484</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.895774</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">47.457496</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">43.060021</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="eng"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://Service=sde:sqlserver:gis; Database=gisdata; User=gisadmin; Version=sde.DEFAULT</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">SDE Feature Class</formatName></distorFormat></distributor><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distFormat><distTranOps><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distTranOps></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE" value="26847">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Maine_East_FIPS_1801_Feet</identCode><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">7.9.4</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="WadingbirdWaterfowl"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">0</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20130510</mdDateSt></metadata>
